

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

Software Engineering Manager | Phoenix, Arizona

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

EXPERIENCE

Theorem | Los Angeles, California

Engineering Manager: March 2021 – Present

• Manage a team of remote software engineers, overseeing the architecture, development, and delivery of custom software for clients.

Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona

Staff Engineer: May 2019 – March 2021

Senior Developer: December 2018 – May 2019

- Lead a team of developers and testers by prioritizing tasks, delegating duties, and guiding projects to successful and on-time delivery.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development, allowing developers to rapidly begin coding and reducing the time needed to deliver a minimum viable product.
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage in all applications, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and led successful effort to refactor applications to follow these guidelines.
- Implemented a Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories, increasing team throughput and code quality.

Carvana | Tempe, Arizona

Software Engineer: February 2018 - December 2018

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com using C#, .NET & .NET Core.
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for vehicle inventory search engine (JavaScript ES6+, React & Redux).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

CBRE | Tempe, Arizona

Application Developer: January 2011 - February 2018

GIS Technician: March 2008 - January 2011

- Developed web applications which provided mapping, site selection, and data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients using ASP.NET MVC.
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis using C#, .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, and Python.
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).
- Created custom maps and market research reports for brokerage staff, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.

ABOUT ME

My name is Matthew Callahan, and I am a player-coach in the software world: I enjoy writing code as well as leading my team and mentoring developers. I have over ten years of experience in software development and continuing to learn the ever-changing landscape of programming is my passion.

CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

Blog: mfcallahan.blog

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Frameworks

.NET & .NET Core, Node.js, Angular, React, ArcGIS

Testing

NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium

Dev Tools

Azure, Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Splunk, SQL Server